A really good thing to have in your studio if you're producing a lot of pieces is a damp area that's designated to keep pieces damp.
Now, the way that this works, I have built into a metal shelving unit, I've added side pieces and then cross bars.
And shelves can come in and out of these cross bars.
When I'm throwing pieces that I take directly off the wheel, I can set them right onto this shelf, and then slide it into this damp area, or if I've thrown them on a bat I can set the bat on the shelf.
Now the benefit of doing this, is that you don't have to throw plastic over pieces that are still very wet, which can often leave marks, it can deform them, it can do a lot of things that are kind of unpleasant and cause you to do a lot of work later that you didn't want to have to do.
So this has a front door made of plastic.
It's completely enclosed, all the way around, with plastic, and then it's just got a large drape that comes over the front.
Now, when I'm going to leaves for a long period of time in here and I want them to stay damp, I'll spray down the damp area, and then I will tape the sides shut, so that no air flow will go through there.
And on not incredibly dry days you can keep things in there for days on end without having a problem and they'll stay damp for you.
It's a really great way to save you some time and save you some effort.